

CONTACT ME

+49 179 103 7171 claudinei.bido@gmail.com Berlin, Germany

SOCIAL

linkedin.com/in/bidoc github.com/bidodev

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) / SASS
React / Redux
Node.js / Express
MongoDB / Mongoose
SQL / MySQL Server
Technical Support
Linux Servers / AWS
Git / GitHub

LANGUAGES

Firebase

Portuguese - Native English - Full professional proficiency German - Professional working proficiency Italian - Professional working proficiency

HERE'S MY STORY:

I'm a Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript/ES6 / Node.js / React / Redux / Express / MongoDB, side experiences on C / C++ / Pascal / Delphi / LUA / SQL / PHP, System Administration, Technical Support, Databases, AWS, Management.

I define myself as a problem solver who loves challenges when there is a problem I will work towards a solution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tutor

DCI DIGITAL CAREER INSTITUTE GMBH

- Responsible for helping students learn and reviewing exercises
- Explaining how to solve problems and checking completed work
- Helping students develop study skills and organization techniques

Social Media Moderator

ARVATO - BERTELSMANN / MAJOREL SEP 2017 - OCT 2019

- Ensuring a quality experience for all users according to the clients terms of service
- Management of online social media platform content
- Investigate and resolve customer queries

Linux Systems Administrator

SONTAG COMMERCIAL AUTOMATION

FEB 2014 - DEC 2016

- Development of scripts in Shell Script, PHP / Lua in order to automate tasks
- Setup and administration of Servers (LAMP, Node JS). Networks analysis, backup routines
- Designer and scalability of the hardware and cloud (AWS)

Technical Support Technician

SMO INTERNET PROVIDER

JAN 2012 - NOV 2013

- Customer Service support and miscellaneous product updates
- Setting up and designing servers and clouds (VMWARE) for commercial automation
- · Maintenance of hardware, component updates, fault correction

IT Technician - Internship

SENAI - SERVICO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAGEM INDUSTRIAL MAR 2007 - JAN 2010

- Maintenance of servers and desktops for corporate clients
- Implementation of personal and corporate networks
- Technical Customer Support

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Course

DCI DIGITAL CAREER INSTITUTE GMBH SET 2019 - JAN 2021

Computer Science

UFFS - UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DA FRONTEIRA SUL FEB 2010 - JAN 2012

IT Computer Technician

SENAI - SERVICO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAGEM INDUSTRIAL FEB 2007 - JAN 2010